# FELLIPE SILVESTRE

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Former penetration tester with 3 years of industry experience in international teams, currently seeking a career transition into Software Engineering, aiming to leverage relevant cybersecurity knowledge into building secure, reliable and user friendly applications, in order to solve real world problems.

#### CONTACT

+55 61 99869-6527

fellipe.silvestre@outlook.com

Luziânia, Goiás

https://github.com/silvestr3/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fellipe-silvestre/

#### SKILLS

Problem solving

Cybersecurity

Web application development

Scripting and automation

#### EDUCATION

**Technologist - Cyber Defense** 

#### **FIAP**

2020 - 2022

**MBA - Fullstack Development** 

#### Rocketseat

2024 - Ongoing

#### LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native

English Fluent

Thai Beginner

### SOFTWARE PROJECT

#### Caramelo POS - WEB Full Stack







- Complete POS (Point of Sale) solution for Motorbike store. Provides means to manage inventory, customers, sales, employees, multiple storage locations, generate sale receipts, and so on (application is ongoing development, more features are being designed and built).
- Live demo : https://demo.caramelopos.com/
- Username: demouser
- Password: demopassword

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Cybersecurity Analyst**

Tempest (Brazil)

2023-Currently

- Performed penetration testing assessments on various kinds of applications, such as Web, mobile, API, desktop, and so on, in order to uncover security vulnerabilities or misconfigurations that could lead to compromise;
- Worked closely to client's development teams to address vulnerabilities and suggest mitigations;
- Researched about most modern development and security practices, in order to
  ensure that the assessed applications apply the fittest resources to protect
  users privacy, infrastructure reliability and overall enterprise's information
  security.

#### **Penetration tester**

Skylight (Australia)

2022-2023

- Performed multiple types of cybersecurity assessments, including penetration testing, secure code review, Red Team exercises, and so on;
- Developed a CLI tool in Python to manage virtual servers from different providers (such as Vultr, DigitalOcean, AWS), and provide an interface for my technical peers to easily create, destroy, configure or use virtual servers on the cloud through the CLI;
- Deployed and maintained several applications and cloud infrastructures for internal use;

# **Cybersecurity Analyst**

DCIT (Brazil)

2021-2022

- Performed Web Application penetration testing engagements, and helped customers fix security gaps;
- Researched about latest security vendors and products to determine their efficiency to protect customer assets;
- Worked closely to Blue Team to help them identify attack patterns and respond to incidents on customer's assets and networks.